Before we go any farther in the
Series of pictures i want to make a few comments about banks
Banks are special
They are among the most regulated institutions in the world and they are very different from non-financial corporations
Their differences
Primarily stem from their ability to take deposits
I deposit
Is a kind of loan when
When you lend money to a friend you know to give me the loan
When you lend money to a corporation in general you are aware of the credit risk of that loan
Get when you make a loan to a bank
You think you have money in the back
In fact you just let it be
Deposits are different from other loans however be
Because there are
Offers made by bank
To the general public
To accept loans
Repairable on demand or at short notice so
So these two characteristics
The fact that they are made to the general public and that the fact that they re payable on demand orange short note
This means that the difference of the loans
And it's this difference that give
Bank deposits their liquidity
And make bank deposits
Societies money
Most payments in the world today are made through exchanging bank deposits
Banks are able to exchange deposits because
Because not only can they change the beneficiary of
A deposit
That is held in their own bank
But they can also instruct the central bank
Debit their own account with the central bank
Penn credit
The account of another bank
For the benefit of the ultimate pee
This membership of the payment system
That allows banks to dominate payments in our society as well
Let's look at the end report
Owl city group
One of the largest financial institutions in the world and you can see that
Citibank also has a statement of income and balance sheet
If we choose to summarize the balance sheet of citibank into a managerial balance sheet
Then we find shaped differently
From that of other balance sheet we've looked at
First of all it
It's highly leveraged
The equity of city
Rangers from 2012 to 2014
M11
13%
Secondly it
It relies tremendously on short-term debt
It's short-term debt
Rangers from 68 -
Is 72% of the balance sheet
The right away if
If we use the same standards as we used for non-bank corporations we would save the bank have no solvency
And load acquitted most of the bank
Fixed assets
Are not property plant and equipment all they are in
Investments
And loans to consumers and corporations and the other assets
Which include
Physical fixed assets
Are only a tiny fraction of the balance sheet
The assets of city court
Car 1.8 trillion dollars
That's about 15 times the size of the assets of sinopec
It's sweet corn
Is not the largest bank in the world the largest bank in the world is the industrial commercial bank of china
Can its total assets
Are about twice the size of speakers
Global banks are among the largest corporations in the world by assets
Largest liability is deposits
I'm only
Banks
Or other financial institutions that are
Granted deposited and powers
Can take those deposits
Banks have deposit with the central bank
Only banks and other
Clearing financial institutions
Can have deposit from the central banks
Banks are hiding everest
And most of the assets of banks
Are fixed income assets
And if you looked at
Happy
Income statement of citigroup
He would find out that most of the revenue
Comes from
Net interest revenue
And
Non-interest revenue when a non interest revenue is the
The revenues for providing
Audi financial services
Show all the revenues of the group
Financial services
Another
Interesting aspect of
The income statement is
Is the provision for credit losses for
From the large portion
The current provision for credit lock credit losses
Is 7.4 billion dollars so far i've discussed the fact that
Banks are different from non-financial corporations
The different from non-banks
The truth is that the line is not that clear hoffman laroche is not a financial institution
And yet its long-term debt
Includes
Retirement benefits and retirement ben
Jennifer liabilities
These retirement benefit liabilities
Bar
Lightning
Claims on insurance company because hulk
Open the roach is providing pensions
And medical care for its employees
Toyota corporation
The largest single category of assets within the net worth and capital requirements
His
Finance receivables and net
These are
Loans customers and leases to customers of vehicles
Show toyota
Pinterest the financial service business
In order to stimulate its customers to
To purchase their vehicles
Some non banks have their own payment systems and they have huge investment portfolios
I'm thinking of alibaba with it's a leap a network which dominates the payment
An online purchasing
Can someone banks
On their own backs general electric orange 10 bank
Moreover when's the surgery of general electric
General electric capital corporation
So dominates its financial statements
The general electric typically shows
Cheat on
On a pro forma basis with
Without general electric capital corporation
Here you can see that
Cash within
Lgeccu
The non-cash net working capital balances within without gcc the fixed assets
Short-term debt
And the long-term debt are
Are so dramatically different
That it looks like a completely separate corporation
Stimulating the company
The show on a pro forma basis
What is the counselor look like
Were it not for its financial subsidiaries
The line between banks and non-financial corporations is drawn in law and i'm company practice find a
Disney information service
Finance opportunities are evolving very rapidly as
Have the technology revolution is impacting information that forms the major part of
The financial transactions
Financial professionals in nonfinancial firms
Often wish to use their own expertise to make money and company management
Masterchef the strategic fit
An acceptable level of risk
In providing such financial services