I'd like to conclude
This section on financial ratios are talking about operating efficiency ratios
By this time you realize there are many many racial to talk about the common size income statement and common size balance sheet
Cheats
Profitability ratios dupont analysis liquidity ratios leverage ratios and now we're talking about
Operating efficiency
Operating efficiency is primarily concerned
Turnover
How long a time at 2
Takes for a given
Downset
Tv placed
Assets take up
Financing
Is expensive
So if we can reduce the assets
Weekend reviews
The financing
We're going to look
Components of
Of the worst capital requirement the major accounts of non-cash short
Short-term assets
Accounts receivable
And inventories
Interested in analyzing
Speed at which accounts receivable and inventory turnover
Accounts payable is a free form of financing
Are liabilities
Short-term debt
Counter depth
Inequities
Are contributed by investors
Actually wish to invest in the firm
To make a prof
Accounts payable
Simply vera
About the wii
02 our suppliers
Our suppliers don't wish to invest in our firm butt
Suppliers are forced to invest in our firm
Judy
Industry practice
That allows us to pay later
Ford
Supplies that we receive now
From this point of view
If account payable are truly free
It is in our interest
Maximize the accounts payable
In order to minimize the working capital
Set the ratios that were going to be looking at in operating efficiency concern
Inventories and accounts receivable have
As well as accounts pa
Santa pics inventory turnover is 11.
3/8
Times two that means if you take the cost of goods sold
Can you divide by the
Average inventory
Sorry
He'll come out with the number
11.38
We can express that in terms of days sales in inventory days sales inventory
Is simply
The reciprocal of the inventory turnover
X
365 days
On average it
It's
Products
Are kept in inventory for 32 days
We can similarly calculator receivables turnover
Receivables turnover
Is simply be
Sales
/
Average
Accounts receivable
Notice
That for receivables turnover
We use the
Where can you be
Because accounts receivable
Are measured at the
Sales price in the accounting stay
Warehouse for inventories
We use the cost of goods sold because
Because inventories are recorded at the cost of goods sold
In the balance sheet
Weekend express
Receivables turn
Turnover
10 days of sales receivable
Simile
We take the reciprocal
Of the receivables turnover and
10 x 365 begins
Pictures 365 days in the year
And that gives us the number of days that it takes for
For receivable to
I go through our
Count sheet
On average
We hold receivables for 10 days
We can do the same calculation
Which respect to
Pitbulls
That gives us then turn over
Of 11x
Pitbulls
Turnover on average
11x per year
Days payable is simply the reciprocal
The payables turnover
X 3
Show on average
We take 31.36 days to make
Make payment to
Watch pliers
We can look at the whole of net working capital
How to calculate a turnover for that
Notice that for
Sanipac
This is a negative number
Why is it a negative number
You remember
From china pack
Does working capital requirement was negative
In fact for side effect
Get accounts payable
Are greater than its accounts receivable plus
Inventories
That means that sinopec get
Catnip
Free financing
Its suppliers
Finally the calculator
Asset turnover
This asset turnover
Looks at total sales
/
Average assets
So this is the
Assets the beginning of ear
Plasticity interior
Divided by 2
To give us the number of times that
Assets are turned over
Every year and 4 side effects
A turnover almost
Twice
Prettier
Hoffman laroche
How to much lower turnover
Agency that inventories
Turnover only
About twice a year
Whereas for side effect that turned over 11 times
Receivables
Turn over only about five times per year
Whereas for side effects
They turned over
35x
Now you might say well
That's because hoffman
The drug company
And sinopec
Is a
Refiner of oil
Can you be right
What makes a lot of sense when
When you're looking at industry ratios
Compare like-with-like
Go into a company and
And comparative with other companies in the
The industry
We went to a website more
Morningside
Collected
Russian skater 4
Days sales outstanding
Inventory turnover
Pitbulls.
Penn found out that on average when
When you compare
Roshe with the industry leader
Pfizer we found out the trash at higher turnover
And this
Days in inventory
When did pfizer
It had about the same days sales outstanding and it's
Pitbulls.
Where substantially less
Danforth
Fighter
It was able to get that free financing
Dan pfeiffer
I've been using the word free
Refinancing rather too freely
And the reason why is it trade supplier
Often give a discount if they make payment earlier
For example of supply army office terms of 2/10
Net
210 musette me get a 2% discount if
If we pay in 10 days
And we have to pay the full amount
If we pay in 30 days
Can we must pay in 30 days now we can calculate what the implied interest rate is bile
Police the simple formula
The interest rate for trade discounts is
Is the full payment
Divided by the discount payment
Power 365/2 days - discount days
Going back to
Example that
He just looked at
2-10 net 30
Mean step
We can pay $100
In 30 days
Or we can pay
$98 at
Happy end of 10 days
That should be raised in order to convert to an annual rate of interest
^
Free headphones
/
Why because it is
20 day financing
Anders 365 days in a year
And then of course or subtract from that one
1.204
To the power
.5
The swan
Which is equal to
About
Express
What time are you going to study of proficiency
I wish to turn over assets more rapidly and i'll and liabilities more slowly to save equity and debt capital
Ratios of companies
She be compared to companies in similar industries to make appropriate comparisons as to what constitutes inefficient
Efficient use of resources and the free financing of payables make him at a very high price