Dad like to say a few words about arbitration speculation building on electro that i gave earlier
On my
Market efficiency
And using as an example for an exchange transactions that talked about in the last lecture
Search for getting are term straight arbitrage
Is the simultaneous purchase and sale of securities with identical cash flows to yield the risks pro
One of these securities may be so called synthetic security
Made up of more
More than one underlying security and the second typically and underlying security
Speculation
Is the taking of risk
In order to earn an expected profit the law of one price is an economic concept
What is it to securities
For portfolio security with the same cash flows should
Should be priced the same
If it can be purchased and sold by the same agency
City arbitrage transaction is a very simple one
You buy the cheap security issue or borrowing sell the expensive security
How do you enjoy the difference
Because arbitrage is so incredibly profitable there are many traitors that
Devote their entire life to taking advantage of them as soon as they appear
Because of that activity arbitrage opportunities are rare and fleeting the search for arbitrage
Imposes relative price efficiency but
Tween assets considered an example of arbitrage this is the relationship
Call covered interest rate parity
Covered interest rate parity shows the arbitration post relationship between the
Current exchange rate
Forward-rate which is the price of foreign exchange for delivery in the future but cold today
Heavy interest rates prevailing in the domestic and foreign money markets
Forward-rate
Is equal to the spot rate times
Oneplus the domestic interest rate
8 รท 1 +4
For an interest rate
1 plus the interest rate can be
I thought of as the return of the asset
And here we have the relationship based on
The direct quote if the
Forward-rate is greater than the spot rate
X theme
Rate of return
The best currency divided the rate of return in the foreign currency
Alice is your lucky day that
Let's take an american example from the hong kong market
Hierba quoting the direct quote from the hong kong point of view on
On us dollars for this is hong kong dollars per us dollar
Let's see the spot is 7.81
Dunkin donuts us dollar the forward that it say the price for us dollars
Expressed in hong kong dollars
Deliverable in one year
Yes
7.9
Hong kong dollar to u.s. dollar
Interest rate in hong kong dollars is 3% per annum
Heavy interest rate in the us is 3.1% per annum if you do the numbers
Forward us dollars
Mark spencer
Forward price of us dollars
Are expensive
Relative to the synthetic forward
What are synthetic forward
Traders have trading limits to the
They're only allowed by their can
Appliance systems internal compliance
2000 amount of money
Let's say the trading limit for the
This traitor is 100 million on
Icon dollars
Bumper selling the
Expensive
Forward with
Which is selling the us dollar forward
We can
Use a maximum
Of 100 million home
Hong kong dollars in the contract
Good on the contract in one year
He will be receiving hong kong dollars because
Cash we are selling us dollars you need to contract
Search that
Barbie seat of hong kong dollars
The offset
Can a debt obligation with taking in hong kong dollars
We borrow an amount of hong kong dollars
That will have a principal plus interest
You in one year's time
Of 100 million hong kong. 100 million dollars
/
1.032
3% is the interest rate
Music we will receive today
97 million
3 + 78
Dollars in $0.64 home
Hong kong
We are contracting
Cell
U.s. dollars forward
Kfc
Forward price hits
7.9 hong kong dollars
U.s. dollar
Is amount of us dollars equal 200 million
Divided by 7.
U.s. dollars
12 million
And $0.85
So we need to invest an amount of money
Ge quote
12 million
$227.85
We're investing that
U.s. dollars
At the rate of
3.1
Percent
Show me
I need to invest us dollars 12 million
658227 $0.85
Divided by 1.031
Navigate we invest today
12 million
$621 + 58
Where do we get that money
We have to buy that money
Spot it
In order to make the investment
For buying at smart money
With hong kong dollars
How much hong kong dollars does it take
It takes
12 million
Six hundred twenty one dollars and
$0.58
Times the current spot rate of
Dollars and
$0.80 hong kong dollars
Current u.s. dollar
4 hong kong dollars 95 million
For the 48
M32
Sex
That is an amount of hong kong dollars we have to give up today
We've received hong kong dollars 97 million
78 and 64 stamps from
The borrowing
That we have done
In order to repair
100 million hong kong dollars
In one year's time
That means we have a net profit
Of the difference between the amount received today
Animal to be give up today
A in order to buy our us dollars
That amount is hong kong dollars
1000003
$321,930.32
Free
Today
Risks
The clearly
Everyone in the world
Who is doing the same thing as we are doing
Who is not blind will
We'll see the forward rate on us dollars
Go to hong kong
It's overpriced
Relatives of the synthetic forward
The synthetic forward
How do you know if borrowing in hong kong dollars
And investing in us dollars
Can converting a spot rate
Do you have to work very fast
Because when you sell the forward
You are he
Hitting other people's bids to you drive down the price of the forward
When you buy the spot you
You are lifting other people's ask rates
So you lift the price of the spot when you borrow hong kong dollars
Can large volumes you tend to push up the
Interest rates of hong kong dollars
And when you invest in us dollars and large volumes you tend to press you
U.s. dollar market interest rates cu
Do you have to work fast because these
For transactions
What time to push the
Tv
Forward-rate in
Into equality with
What's a synthetic forward rate
And that's what we mean when we say
Covered interest rate parity
Is an arbitrage relationship
This equality
Is held together by the actions of traders around the world that are pushing
This relationship
Entry quality
I want to go with you some other foreign exchange rate parity
But the rest of the parodies the wii
Discuss
Arnot arbitrage relationships
Before we go on to
The other foreign exchange parities
I'd like to bring your attention to
To the
Format of the
Covered interest rate parity
Formula
We expressed it at the forward rate equal to the
Spot times
The relative
Returns in the domestic and the foreign mark
Markets
But going forward i shift the spot term
From the return side of the four of the formula
Tv
Foreign exchange side of the formula
This facilitates comparing coveted street parody with
Is uncovered in strip parody
Relative
Power parity
International fisher effect
Can the fisher effect
Uncovered interest rate parity
It's a relationship between the forward rate and the expected value of the future spot
It's
Affected
She speculation
How to arbitrage
Ford rate / the spot rate is equal to the
Heart rate / the spot rate
Or more simply the
Forward
Is equal to the expected future
Picture spot rate
Think of this profit opportunity
You are risk-neutral speculator
You're going to get hong kong dollars 100 million
You're certain
Hong kong government
Successfully defend the peg for
Produced year
Current spot rate is
7.8 hong kong dollars
Per us dollar
Forward-rate
Is hong kong dollars
7.9 per us dollar what
What would you as a speculator do
Sell the us dollar forward because
Cat status
Spencer relative to your expectations
Then you wait for one year and you hope you're right through
To the form contract at the end of the year
He would deliver
U.s. dollars
12 million
227 +
$0.80
That's with certainty
Why because you contracted today
Deliver in one year's time
The us dollar equivalent
To the forward contract
I have a 100 million
At the maximum that you
Can you receive in one year the hong kong dollars 100 million dollars
Of course you have to
Get the u.s. dollars and
And so you do so with those hong kong dollars you buy in one year at the future spot rate in
Enough u.s. dollars to satisfy the forward contract
To your spending and
An expected 12 million
$227.85
At the expected
7.8
Hong kong dollars be us
U.s. dollar spot rate
And that spin
Hong kong dollars 98 million
7 + 34001 + $77.23
That's less than 100 million hong kong dollars that you receive through the 4 with contract
If you would enjoy a hong kong dollars
1 million
$822.77 profit
If you're right
The actions of which beatle speculators will tend to push the four
Forward-rate
Youtube equality or near equality
With the expected future spot rate
As the speculators so
Shelvey expensive suit
Security
And purchase the chi
Cheap security
The most foreign exchange traders are not with neutral
The closer positions on a daily basis and yet
Uncovered interest rate parity
Requires
Holding open positions
4 weeks
Mansour
Or even years the next parody relationship is purchasing power parity
Purchasing power parity is a long-term debt
Determinants of foreign exchange rates
Search that
The expected
Spot rate over the
Hot rate
Is equal to the ratio
Of
Home currency invoicing
Haitian
Two foreign currency
Purchasing power parity
From the
The idea of commodity price parity
The exchange rate
Equalizers the difference of
A commodity price
Prices for
Tween countries
Show
Price
Evade
In the foreign currency
Should be equal to the
Price of the good in the domestic currency
/
Current spot rate
So this is the direct quote on
Honda foreign currency
What home currency / 4
Foreign currency
Or you can express this is the price
X the spot rate the direct quote in the spot rate
Is equal to the price in the home currency
We can derive relative purchasing power parity
From commodity price
Price parity
The price of the four
Foreign currency
X the spot rate
Should be equal to the price of a good in the home currency
And the
Price
In foreign currency at some future time
Should be equal to the
Price
Foreign currency
Happy current time
X 2
Inflation rate
Plus one package deal
The inflation return
From the
Current period
Until the future.
I just got to do a little bit of
Manipulation here
The
Price
Time
Is tiffany
Spot
At time t
Temptu price
Thyme tea
Price in foreign currency times 0
Dick smith
People to the price
At home at home
X 0
Show
Conceit or equal i can
Justified
First expression
Find the second expression
Mount i can also substitute
I can substitute for the
The price
In
Foreign currency
Time for the price in
In-home currency
Foreign currency at time t
Is simply
Equal to the
Price
Foreign currency
At time zero
Oneplus t
Placing right
In-home currency
At time t
Is also
Emily equal to the
Price in
In-home current get time zero
Times dmv
Placing right
Take this expression
Can substitute in
This expression
And
Substitute in
Here so i can catch
This
What's this
Can cancel this
Bringing
Disturb
Around 2
Side of the equation
We're left with
The relationship
Bentley
Expected
Spot over the current spot rate
Equal to
The
Pollution rate in the
Home currency
/ the inn
Inflation rate in
In the foreign currency
And this is relative pressure
Power parity
Relative purchasing power parity you can
Can be written
Fat in a slightly different way we get the expected depreciation of the foreign currency
Roughly equal to the
Home current inflation rate
- - 4
Foreign currency in
Section 8
Purchasing power parity
Is useful but it's not useful in the arbitrage sense and it's not even very useful for
Speculation
Except on a very small set of goods
Freddy kevin good app sleeper
Purchasing power parity
Can't hold it
In the absence of
The barriers to trade him
It works very well if there's cost of sand rapid shipping
Example for financial securities
Where ownership of a financial security
Can be transferred instantaneously around the world at little cost
It will work very roughly
4 easily shipped commodities like oil
Green paper and wood
Wilkerson park parody
Only
Very approximately in the medium-term say 3 to 10 years
That means it's useful in medium-term exchange rate prediction
Is the deviations from purchasing power parity
Opb first over the medium-term
We seen a number of parity relationships
Covered interest rate parity
Which works through arbitrage
Uncovered in straight parody which works to speculation purchasing power parity which
Which works through long-term tree
Create pressure
Interpretation of ship
Is a
An investment relay
Nation ship the interest rate or the return on interest
Have two components an inflationary component
Dad
Real interest rate component the
The international fisher
Affect
Search the real rate interest
Should be equal
Weighted worldwide
As
Capital markets become
A more integrated
You can break down by definition
The interest rate of the home currency
And the foreign currency
Into two parts in a place that compose
And a real component
International capital markets are integrated
These two real components
Become equal
Cancel that cancel each other out
And you can see with god
Complete
Pentagon of parodies
Arbitrage or the law of one price the very powerful
Horse for holding derivative financial securities inc
Into alignment with
Underlying securities
Speculation is a far less powerful for
Horse and the long-term relationships
Of international fisher effect
And purchasing power parity
Kevin long-term parities
Have exchange rates