Zillions of retail and institutional investors buy and sell billions of dollars
Corporate stocks bonds
Derivatives everyday
Deep-fried pacific fine
Financial services for this activity and those services can be a job for you
Market
Treating
Gives liquidity to
Corporate stocks bonds and
Contributors
Market makers stand ready to bid to
X
An offer to sell securities at a higher price
Hoping to make the difference in return for the
What is a pear
If many sellers and buyers in
Aggregate
Are prepared to transact in large volumes
Then a single small shareholder entering the market
When do so without moving the market against him
Investors and speculators
Just talk
To identify under under price stocks to buy an overpriced ops 2
The cell what does the corporate treasurer actually care if
She personally owns
Shares of the company
Party fair
Compensation package
Applicator for own investments
Then her wealth will rise as the stock price rises if she plans that the company in future
Will issue equity
Then she wants the stock price to be high
The company will receive more
More money from
When you claims that issues
But you should remember that
Stocks on stock exchanges
Are trading between investors in the
In the secondary market
Clarify what i mean by the secondary market
I'd like you to return to the managerial balance sheet
Allow me to
The
Manager of balance sheet
And so instead of having a
Equity on the ball
Bottom of a time
I put
Equity on the top of the claims
Parallel to
Now in the corporation wishes to issues equity
You can see that it issues new shares to the investor
For which the investor pays cash
This is called the primary market
And this differs from
The secondary market
Where investors sim
Tempe sell already issued shares
To another
Let's look at real stock
Price
The stock is general electric has the ticker symbol ge and it's listed on the new york stock
Exchange this is the daily stock price changes
On the 14th
Make
15 and the closing price was $27.41 this is reported by
Bloomberg business
But you can get the same kind of information if you go to yahoo or google
4 morningside or other financial information providers
The market value of a stock is simply the
Number of shares outstanding
X the price of the shares we can find the number of shares outstanding here as 10
Is 10075.93 million shares outstanding
410.075 billion shares outstanding
We could have gotten it outstanding shares for
From the most recent financials
But if we done that we might have missed
Share issuances
And repurchases that
That occurred since
The date of the financials if we look at the market value of ge week
I can see it
Pinpoint
593 bill
Billion shares
X 2
$27.41 or 276.18 bill
Billion dollars
Now it's interesting to compare the market value of the equity of a corporation
To its book value that it's a tooth
To the value that the
Counts show
On the
Financial statements
Shareholders equity
Is 100
At 8
.6 billion dollars
The market
To book ratio is often called the price to book ratio
And that ratio
Parsippany 276.18
Divided by 108 points
Orc
2.5
54 x if you go back to bloomberg you can see that they record the price to book ratio
They calculate the price to book ratio for you
2.54 times here
Is the price right
Where is the stock price too high or too low if the price is right to know
What would you do
Define the stock
If they were too high
What would you do if you sell it
I didn't have a stock in
In order to sell it
What you could do was to borrow it from somebody else
And sell it at the current price
Hope that the stock will then go down and
And then
Biotin
The market at the lower price and return those chairs that you borrowed the
This is called selling the stock short
Which financial theory is based on the premise that the market is efficient
The price is right but
Actually market efficiency is an empirical matter when must tested to
Find out whether it is true that
The definition of an efficient financial market
Is that
It's one in which prices always fully reflect available information one can identify three different forms
Forms of stock market efficiency
A strong semi strong and weak the idea of strong form efficient c is that the stock price will
Benefit information what does would imply is that inside information
Nation could not exist in
Insiders are typically
The managers and directors of the company
We might have information that would cause the stock price to go up
It's good information or the stock price to go down if it's bad
Bad information
And they might not have disclosed at the market one of the legal principles
Of
Share trading
Is that
Insiders
Are not allowed to use it
Insider information
To make money
So
Stock prices cannot be strong form efficient
Because if they were there were no such thing that's inside your information
We know that insider information exists
Chevy strong
Efficiency may exist
In semi-strong efficiency
All publicly available information
Is reflected in the stock price
This would imply that to an analyst you
Using public information
There's no way for that analyst through
You better analysis
To determine what stocks for underpriced
Overpriced
And the third
Stock market
Justin c
This week former fishin c
What week form efficiency says is it the current price
Reflect pass prices
Another way of saying it is
Is it there are no gains to be had
From studying the
House
Prices
If the market is weak form efficient
Then
Sharks would involve no
Under adjustment
Moreover adjustment
Wendy in
Information hit the market
Then the information is instantly impounded in
In the market
Let's look at the path of a stock
Price
Our time
Assume there's no information
Vista market
Until this point in time
At that point in time good information hits tomorrow
The market is efficient
Fully in pounds
Secret information
At that point
And the stock price
Twin you
Higher level
Market adjust slowly
Tell me have
Price
If the market over
Over reacts and then comes down
We face
This kind of a price
Price adjustment
Over market reaction
Slow market reaction
Lead 2 acetate
Mystikal
Passion
That an analyst
Could analyze
10 used to
Predict future stock price
The implications of market efficiency
Is
Let the market price is sufficient
Statistic
It's
All do you need to know
It's with ground however -
I'm just down the most analysts
Believe that
Market price
Well the best number
Tampa bay have
As a starting point
It's not efficient stats
Most analysts believe
Market efficiency works only
Some of the time
And only for some traded claims
They believe that good fundamental analysis
Huge profits
Set one can
Analyze publicly available information and
Into that analysis
Identify underperforming
Andover performing stocks
Invest in the underwear underperforming stocks
The gains from that
If the analyst believes or
Used
Technical analysis that analyst believes that analyzing
Atlanta stock prices can be profitable
You probably heard the terms the head and shoulders the double top bottom
Momentum
Moving averages lines support
Resistance
Candlestick charting
Wave theory
All of these reflective leaf of analysts
The stock price itself
Can be analyzed to
Catellus
What are the stock price is going to go in future
In summary
I'd like to say
That a liquid market gives an extremely important estimate
Office securities value
Even
If it is not a sufficient statistic
For the value of a security