I'm going to continue my discussion of financial ratios
By looking at
Call fancy
And liquidity
The firm is liquid if it can meet its obligations when they come to you
Loss of equity
A firm is solvent
The value of assets
Exceed the value of a liabilities
In finance there are three major decisions
Mermaid body core
Corporate treasurer
The size of the couch cushion
The decision as to whether one to have long-term
Debt
What short-term debt
And the third decision is the capital structure decision
Ave
Equity
So this firm is liquid
Liquid because it's short-term debt
Is small
Relative to
It's cash equivalents
Gears are rough diagram of the managerial balance sheet
And if the short-term debt holders
Recall the debt
Obviously that dad at shortened equity paid out of cash and we're left with
A balance sheet
It still has a
A little bit of cash
Cash reserve
And
No short-term claimants
I can push the company
Indiana quality
However that same company
All the liquid
Yes actually
How do leveraged
It is at risk
Positivity
Because the assets
Could suffer a decline in value
And losses
To both
Yes holders
And equity holders
Credit that was an example of a
Affirmed
Which liquid butt
It became insolvent
Here's a firm that is solvent but
What is a liquid
You can see that it has a large amount of short-term debt
Relative to its
More liquid assets
Cash and cash equivalents being very liquid they could be paid out without any loss
Weston capital requirement
Substantially liquid and fixed assets completely liquid
If there was a calling of the short-term debt
The debt holders demand for repayment
Would result in
Stress
The firm
Only the cash it available for payout
The firm with the unable to liquidate its work
Working capital requirement in fixed assets
At a fair value
And therefore it would suffer distress
Did the stress might even lead to it being petition the into bankruptcy
If the debtor appeared on able to pay payment
And the creditor observe demand
The creditor
And the debtors could propose plans for a settlement by
Pretty with a failure to agree on the plans
Kermit
Pushed into bankruptcy and
Could be liquidated
So clearly
Post solvency
And the quiddity are very important to the
Did the firm. some of the ratios we can use to measure liquidity
The cash ratio
The simplest is simply cash over current liabilities the current ratio current assets / current liabilities
And the quick ratio current assets minus
Inventories
Out of current liabilities
These ratios are easy to calculate
Independence is our
Unambiguously
Placed on the balance sheet and they do give a
Good indication of liquidity of a firm another liquidity indicator would be using the managerial balance sheet
And here we
We have a net stable funding ratio the shows the stable funds phone
Find the knot shop
Subject to withdrawal by the investor to
To have equity in long-term debt divided by the
The need for stable funds
Fixed assets
Can working capital requirement
Are needed to be finance
From stable funds
Sinopec
Show itself to be surprisingly
Liquid
Another quiddity
Is decrease
Current assets
Far far left as current liabilities on
Only about 17
Going down to 60
In 2000
If you subtract the in
Inventories from the current assets
Before dividing them by current liabilities to get the quick crew race
Show me
Pc assembly
Decline
I am the numbers are very low
Furniture
Terms that do not have guaranteed access to
Frequently they see a quick ratio of less than 1
As being problematic this is about one-quarter
The cash ratio is a miniscule at 2% so a withdrawal of 2% of the current liabilities
Take away the entire cash balance and only 82 - 87%
The needs
First eagle funding
Barnett
By actual stable funding
To the other
18%
At is finance
By unstable short-term fun
Treating to roche we see a completely different liquid he picture
The current ratio
There is between 1.35 and 1.74 all the all of liquidity ratios are dropping
They're still very comfortable the quick ratio is above one cash ranges for
From 1/2 to
The three quarters of current liabilities and more stable funding is available then
Can the need for stable funding
There's an excess of stable funding what can explain this difference between sign up
Hack
Roshe one reason
Might be the guaranteed availability of bank funding sinopec
Is a state on enterprise in china the state-owned banks are very comfortable with lending design a peck
Santa probably feels very comfortable in
Can drawing down bank line of credit when
Whenever it wishes to
So it doesn't need the cash balances
Roach doesn't have that kind of a position within the
Swiss economy moreover roche has a strategy of
Purchasing companies with promising intellectual property so
Maintaining a high cash balances and high liquidity
Can help
Roshe
Keep the powder dry for
For acquisitions turning now to leverage or so fancy
Capital structure
Involve step with short-term and long-term
Debt
And equity
Buy the balance sheet identity
We know that acids are
Are equal to 2
Class act
From the balance sheet identity
You can see that
Three measures of
Capital structure
Are essentially identical the debt equity ratio is simply
Total debt divided by total equity
The declaration which
Which is simply debt over assets
Is simply 1-2
The reciprocal
Of the equity mall
The reciprocal of the
Equity multiple
Mississippi
Equity drive
Divided by assets
1 - equity divided by assets is
The assets
Minus equity divided
Guided by assets
Simply dental
Over assets
Is the debt ratio
As we noted for
Which is more
Leveraged
Side effects
But it's
Debt ratio is
Is dropping its
Map from
72% of balance sheet
In 2011
64% of the balance sheet
The long-term debt ratio
Looks at long-term debt
Portion of equity
Some consider that short-term debt
It's not a permanent part of the capital structure
Dr
But in fact
Varies
From time to time
Throughout the year going up and down
As the needs of working capital
Are financing in
Increase or decrease
During the
Operating cycle
Is the company 2
Too heavily leveraged
One way to answer that question is
Is to look at the
Cash available for debt service
10 / the debt service
The narrowest measure of debt service is the interest that is due on the dead
So in both of these measures
Look at interest in
In the denominator
Times interest
Earning take
Pics of attorneys before interest and taxes and / interest
The cash coverage ratio
Ads depreciation and amortization
2 abbott
In order to get a broad measure of cash available
Service center
Interest payments
The times interest earned and
The cash coverage ratio
Range from 6
Answer the company is
Very comfortably able to deal with its debt
Get service require
Apartments
Sinopec
The numbers are
Even
Larger one
Jersey cash coverage ratio
Because side effects of a lot of depreciation to please
Fictional amortization
It's times interest
Coverage ratio
Abbott over interest
Are also
Dr lehigh
We conclude our
Temporary of
Ratios of liquidity and solvency
I remind you that the quality is not the same as solvency but both illiquidity and insolvency with
Would be dangerous to a cup
Policies for maintaining adequate
Cash reserves and setting the
The capital structure of the company
Parkour to the financial strategy
Alpha company