I'd like to continue with the discussion of foreign exchange
By talking about
Managing for
Foreign exchange expose
There are three types
F4
Foreign exchange exposure
Transactions expose
And operating exposure
Bossier
Is
The risk
The accounting perform
Company movie
Adversely affected
To the translation into the home currency
A foreign currency assets and liabilities
And
City consolidation
Can the home currency
Of foreign currency subsidiary accounts
Transaction exposure
Cash flow exposure
It's the risk that
Foreign currency-denominated cash flows
Translated into home current
Currency
Who be adversely affected
What were talking with transactions exposure
About
Contracted
Cash flows
Cash flows that are typically occur
Within the
Humans
2 a year
Operating exposure is a much long
Longer-term concept
In fact it extends throughout the entire life of the come
It's the risk that the home
Home currency
Value
Of future expected cash flows
Will be adversely affected by unanticipated
Foreign exchange price changes
And it's expected cash flows
Can you throw
Entire life of the company
Can contribute to
To the companies
Value
We're not going to talk about operating school
Bossier
Until i talk about it
Net present value today
I'll just be talking about accounting exposure
Transactions expo
First of all accounting or translation expose
Translation exposure is the risk of losses
In the financial statements of a cup
Company when the assets and liabilities
Denominated in non-local currencies
Are subject to adverse changes in
Can exchange rate movements
Whether the company has
Citrus overseas or not it may have monetary assets and liabilities
If these monetary assets and live
Liabilities are denominated in foreign exchange
They will be translated at the spot rate
On the balance sheet date
And then the gains and losses
Associated with these changes
In the value of those
Monetary assets in life
Liabilities
To be reported
In the profit and loss accounts
Whether the assets are
Monetary or dare
Property plant and equipment
Or working capital requirement
All of the assets and liabilities of a foreign domiciled
Foreign currency based of century consolidated into the company's accounts
Arkansas dated by a method
Call the current rate method
Current rate method
In general
Translate
All of the assets and liabilities
Of the century
Update spa
Heart rate
On the balance sheet date
If this process of consolidating
Foreign currency-denominated subsidiaries accounts
If the parent company
Cheats to foreign exchange gains or losses
East canton losses do not go through the proper
Law statement
The debit accredited
Directly to equity
To something called the statement of comprehensive income
So let's look at the accounts of ge
Ge has
Mini sub series located all over the world
And as you can see by this
Statement of comprehensive income
The translation or
Counting games can be considerable so this first line is the net earnings that
Cast from the profit and loss account
Enemy make chevrolet judgments
The adjustments
Investment securities
Anne from pitch
Benefit plans
But two of the adjustments
Are related to foreign exchange
And here we have
Currency translation adjustments
And here we have cash flow hedges
Peter hitches that
That were set up to offset
Is cash flow
Adjustments
And you can see the number 2.729 billion us dollars
His considerable
At 18% of income
This is something that management is likely to worry about
Ali baba's
Foreign exchange translation expo
Bossier
Comes from
Exposures that are
Not associated with cancer
Consolidation of overseas surgeries
It come through
Direct asset and liability accounts
If we go to the red herring
Prospectus page 103
We can see under interest and investment income
The footnote
Arnette interest in investment in
Income
Increased by 84.9%
Virginia beach wouldn't it
Billion
To jimmy beat 39 million
Andy cohen
I want to say that that mainly due to
To foreign exchange losses but
Wooden 2014
Alibaba
Radically
Changed
Translation expose
Bossier
And it did so
By booking
New u.s. debt
Get me to us investments
Of 358 million
U.s. dollars
Handbook to you at u.s. debt
Of 5 billion
U.s. dollars
I give it a net foreign exchange exposure on balance sheet
Of -4
4.643
That is to say
B
Us
Dollar investments
- the us dollar debt
Giving a net translation for an exchange expose
Kosher
Benjamin b
Translated to the balance sheet date of 6.2
One six
Ford
Jimmy b per us dollar
Of
28.8 bill
Alien agenda
That meant that if the us dollar tree
Appreciated by 3%
Alibaba wood lures
.03
X
Million
865 million
Ntb
Alibaba has
Has shorted the
U.s. dollar
On balance sheet
What that means
Is that if u.s. dollar goes up
Alibaba
Deuces
If the us dollar goes down
Alibaba games
Perhaps it's not just a straight bet
Maybe alibaba anticipated
Did in future it will be getting us dollar revenue coming in
In that case alibaba hair
Facebook
A balance sheet head
I want now to turn to transaction expose
Kosher
Stephen ross and his text
Search the transaction exposure is
His short-run financial risk
Rising for the need to buy or sale at unser and prices or rates in the knee
Near future
Note that ross did not even talk
Talk about foreign exchange
Kitty expense
Scope of transactions expose
Bossier
Price risk of
Of any asset
Particular of
Commodities like iron steel
Paper gold so
Silver or the products that are being produced by our company
Why didn't my discussion i'll be only be
Referring to
Foreign exchange
Transaction 6
The word hedging
Comes from
A protective barrier made of
Wood or bricks or plants
Prevent in
Judgement in a property
Here's a picture of a hand around the house
Since the 17th century so for at least the last 300 years
Pictures also taken on a financial meeting
After testing an adjustment for
The head not change the underlying
Transaction that presents the risk
The hedgehog ebooks additional cash flows
That was offset to
The cash flows of the underlying risky transaction
Betty hedges involved river doves
Such as forwards swaps and options
The hedges can also be
Balance sheet hedges
Which is the one that might exist
For alibaba bk
Mini hedges used to riverton
And because these derivatives
Trade in highly liquid markets
Their costs at by their cost i mean
Half of the bed
Did have spreads of this
The bid-ask spread
Around the expected value of that derivative
Typically the cost
Of distributive
Cantaloupe
Show heading
Can reduce the volatility of cash flows
For a relatively low cost
Natural hedge
Is an offsetting operating cash flow
Payable that's rising up
Conduct of business
Financial hedge
Refers to either an offsetting debt obligation such as a
Don't make me may have had with alibaba aur
For some type of financial derivative
Pictures of foreign exchange for
Corporate treasurers may wish to hatch because
Predictions that they have a foreign exchange rate changes are poor
You can often get it wrong
Hitching
Can increase the value of the firm
Simply be
Reducing the volatility of cash flows
That makes the firm less risky to investors
Can hitting with forwards and swap
Kent to be as i said relatively cheap
The corporate treasurers can also wish to speculate
They may wish to speculate
They're good at predicting the future
And if the corporate treasurer
Nearest living or is not too risk-averse
Corporate treasurers want to add value
Most company strength is not
Hot finance
And they should not be encouraged play in the markets get their two companies have
Have corporate treasurers that do have expertise in financial markets
And in order to motivate the high-quality individuals then
Baby given discretion to take financial risks for
Foreign expected return
For example they may wish to take open positions on foreign exchange for coverage is expensive
And prefers red
Relative to forecasts
Or they may wish to make long-term bets on exchange rate movements
Based on macroeconomic analysis
Here is a simple example of hedging a transaction
The treasurer of a us-based multinational corporation in you expect that you're going to be cu
Japanese yen
10 billion in flow in one year
The contracted as a contractor japanese yen in flow
Your home currency is us dollars
You have no opinion on
On what the expected future spot will be
But the spot rate is .83
333 us dollars 400 japanese yen and
And the forward rate
East point 8706 us dollars
For japanese yen
If your direct quote on the japanese yen
10 lies the problem
Correctly
You should quantify the risk here
Here's the japanese yen
Are u.s. dollar pound
From 2010
2 - 2015
And you can see that it is
Activated quiet
Michael are going down to almost 75 yen per us dollar
Up to
225 yen are you
U.s. dollar
Show clearly there is risk with industry
Transaction how do we measure the risk
We can use simple statistical techniques to do so
Calculate the standard deviation of returns
How the exchange rate
Again here is the
How to japanese yen per us dollar from
2010 -
The
Here is where
Where that path came from
This is the direct quote
From the japanese perspective
Find the price of us dollars
And these are the dates
Starting from the
10th of september 2015
And working back
A 2000
Here are the calculations app
The top me have the daily standard deviation
Which is simply the
Sample standard deviation of this vector
And here is so that is
.39% per day
Adhere is the annual standard deviation
We just take the daily standard deviation
And
X 2
250 that's enough
Number of trading days in the year
The power
1/2
Note that over the period
Ivy
Cnn appreciated
9.53% per year
Sew weave
How to find the risk
Hi by saying that the i'm going to assume that there's no excuse
That's what the corporate treasurer believes
And all simply plug the
Standard deviation
Is the annual standard deviation
Into a normal distribution x 1.65 standard deviations
And that gives this
10%
Best to say that
Have to say is 95%
Probability
That we will not lose more
Then 10%. 10% of the principal amount is not trivial by booking the forward we would sell
Japanese yen
10 billion forward in one year with liver the japanese yen 10
An except
Us dollars
87.06 million
The advantages of the forward hedge
Is it tuesday cheap intern
The transaction costs and the forward pricing and to reflect
Forecast
This is the conclusion from the last lecture
Did the forward price is an unbiased predictor of the future spot clean
Clearly
If the forward trades at
At a premium
But we expect no change in the future spot it
It much better to hatch
In this case
Forward
What's trading at a premium
Let it say we received
Higher valuation for the
The japanese yen by booking a
Forward
Then the spot dessert
Us dollars per japanese yen
We believe the current spot but the
The best estimate
Future spot is much better they had them to remain open if the forward is an unbiased predictor of the spot and transit
Directions are not very costly
And we're risk-averse we should have
Remember
Need a 5% probability
Honest transaction
That we would lose more than
10 100th
Billion yen worth of us dollars
What is the forward is at a discount
And you disagree with the forward
Forecast
Then you should consider
In detail the volatility
The forecast
York risk aversion
In conclusion
Foreign exchange
Movements can cause
Considerable
Changes to accounting statements
Cash flows
The risks should be understood
And the risks should be managed