Banking is very important to corporate
Finance
Many corporate treasurers clear pads travel through banking
The vast majority of most firms cash balances
Are held in
In bank deposits
And almost all of corporate payments
Army to debiting and crediting of those deposits and bank that makes up a large proportion
Bobcat financing
Corporate debt can be divided into two types
What type is market-based debt and the other type is financial institution dead
Market-based debt or money market instruments
Galaxy interactive lesson one year
Partial paper
Pete acceptances and short-term notes
Capital market instruments
R
Marketable securities of a greater than one year in duration
Please include medium and long-term notes and bonds
Netflix tuition debt
Include overdraft lines of credit short medium and long term loans
In financial leases
Templeton financial institution dead
Bank that is the most important
What's the relative importance of
Of financial institutions debt
2 market base
A step
It depends
Small and medium-sized enterprises depend entirely on banks other financial institutions because they
I just can't help
Financial markets
Toyota and side effects are very large corporations
But these companies depend about fifty-fifty
On banking and financial market debt
Banks provide about 90% of
The credit in
In germany
Total credit including household credit
But the only provide about 30% of credit in the united states
Developing economies in general have a higher reliance on bank debt then
Can a capital market
Can money market debt
Loans are you either
Fully repaid or their lost
Assuming that the loss is complete
Blender would be different if probability of payment vallone
Time's the return of the loan
Is equal to the rate of
Interest at which the bank fun
Sunflower
For if a probability of payment
Is equal to
Oneplus the island cost to finance of
Kathy valentine
Divided by 1
The return of the loan if the promised return is 5%
And if the all-in cost of the fun
Kansas 3%
Then the break-even probability is
98% what that means is that 50 good loans would have to be booked
For each bad loan
Fed up 90% is a very high level of confidence
This is a far higher level of confidence that is required in most business dealings
Banks are obsessed with me
It's
It's the risk of
The firm the
The landing to losing its value
Ideeli
A banker would know what the value of the assets of the firm isn't all times
I delete the
The bank of which set the terms of the loan
Search that if the firm's value of
Assets
Approach to value of liabilities
Set it say if the equity approaches zero then the banker with call the loan immediately the
The bank of america is the value of the assets
By selling them
Take the proceeds of the sale
And use them to pay off the liabilities of the firm
In such a case
Bank loans with
Delicious
Name of the company that have short-term debt and long-term debt
Paul held by the bank
And it's you that
At the bank
Is
Monitoring closely
Become
Company
Antique watches as there is excessive
Negative sharks
The value of fixed assets
Can reducing the equity
Question
That the company has
We can think of
Set of shocks
Wiping out
The value
Equity
The bank will
Home alone
Q and payable
It will
Fell off the value of the assets
It will repay
From the proceeds the bank loans
Annual cv
The bank
Then we'll be forced
Why because they'll be sufficient
From the sale of the assets
Make repayment of the bank loans
But in fact this
The situation does not occur
Because the moment that the company goes into bankruptcy there is a draw
Drop in the value of the assets
Bankruptcy
In the value of assets
Is due to
Bankruptcy costs
Bankruptcy costs include things like the
Beacon accounting and trustee fees
Loss of value and operation of a company
And theft
Top 50
Is technically known as fraudulent conveyance
Convene of the asset prior to bankruptcy to in
Employees or the owner of the firm bank
Banks mitigate credit risk
Livengood corporations to
Construction the loan and monitoring to reduce the risk
Santa giving the right incentives to the
The borrowers
You are
6 c's of credit analysis
The bankers typically site they want to lend to borrowers with good
Good character
Life is difficult
The wild one
Want to do business with
Dishonest people
Character is critical in landing
They want to lend people that
That have the ability
The managerial and technical capability
Who run the company well
Zipcash flowers because it's cash flows
That make my payment
2 bank loans
Look at the equity cushion the
They want collateral
For example they look to accounts receivable and
Lit up the inventory
And they set the conditions of a loan
Parrot disbursement
Betta fish sticks
Cs of credit analysis
They reflect the extreme bank river
Risk aversion
The comes from limited upside potential
Anna large downside potential
The usefulness of the sixties are not ready headings near me
But they are
Qualitative factors
That should be quantified
Nn
Pretty good credit analysis
It's really a checklist
For the important consider
Situations of credit risk
Corporate financial officer should understand these bankers concerns which are
For shared by all holders of death
Bank debt
Can financial market data