This is the final lap
Electric in the introduction to financial state
The useful to the financial analyst
In this lecture
Htc income statement
That is electric
On the balance sheet
And cash flow statement
Define statements consider
Literally
To allow a stew
Analyze that
Easily the income statement some
Tim rogers
Portents of a company over a period of time usually that. of time is here
Brick could be a quarter
8/2 year
Is the income statement
Let me ask the question
How much money is
Business making
Income of the company is
Is equal to revenue mine
Minus expenses
Let's look at this
Equation in
In terms of a real company
Santa fe corporation
What is the largest oil refinery in china and
And one of the largest oil producers in china
In 2013
Are the revenue of
China peak
2.880 trillion
Jimmy b
And expenses were two point
810 trillium jahmene be giving a net income
Of
Billy and mandy
Expressing these in
Tennis terms
By taking all numbers
Image of revenue the expenses
Outside
Adipex
97.6
Santa fe avenue
Giving
An income of 2
2.4% or a return on sales at sometimes called
5 2.4
Represent
How did we get the numbers what we simplify them from the consolidated financial
Statements prepared under
International financial reporting standards
These numbers refer to footnotes
At the end of
Of the
Statements
Here we've simplified and you can see that
Revenue is made up of two parts
Turnover is largely
Videos of chemical products sales of refined
Oil and
Sales of crude
The
Other operating revenue is
Services
And some rents from
Kim properties
You can see that sign up and gets virtually all of its revenues from
The sale of oil and gas
The refined products
Cost of goods sold
Barbie
Purchases of
Crude oil products in operating
Tyson express
Texas
This item
Is a summation of sales
General administrative expense
Texas
Exploration expense
Dances
Personal expenses
Taxes
Other than
Income tax
These are levees
Daily consumption tax
On products sold
And finally
Other operating expenses and income
Depreciation depletion and amortization
How are non-cash expenses
Allocate
Skechers
Made in previous periods
To the period when revenue is
Generated by those kappa
Capital assets
Depletion
Is
Unique
The extractive industries
The oil and gas reserves avenue
Estimated
And depletion allocates the cost of acquiring and developing the reserves
To the. in
In which they are extra
Sammy's items
Gives you the burn
For interested
4 everett
Subtract from
The net interest
Kingsley
The earnings before
Vortex or ebt
The text item
Is the
Income tax
Corporate income
When's track state taxes
Give you the
Earnings after tax
In finance you have to be so careful about taxes
The average tax rate
Is simply the time
Taxes due
Defined by earnings before
4 tax
The marginal tax rate is
Is the sense of tax
I pay on the last dollar of income
Frequently and finance are interested in
In the marginal tax rate
Where is the average tax rate
Which we calculate tip
Tiffany by the fighting
Buy the earth for
If you see the average tax rate is 26.1% in 2013 and 20
6.3% in 2012
But we know that the
Chinese have a flat tax
25% no matter what the income of a company
Tax will be 25%
Time before tax
Fun projects
There are in the western regions of the prc these are taxed at preferential income rates
Up 15%
On foreign operations 210
Tax rate if it's higher than 45%
Will be the
Tax rate of these
Jurisdiction in which side effect is off
Operating in
In the republic of angola
The tax rate is 50 /
Should a marshall tax rate for project in the western region of the prc would be 15%
Danforth
Projects in the republic of angola for sanipac
50/50
Winnipeg is one of the major state-owned
And enterprises of china
These state-owned enterprises or sos
Are owned partly by the government
There are 116 billion shares outstanding
46 billion are owned
By the china petroleum corporation
So
74% of
China pan
I is actually owned by the state
Another way to say that
Is the public float of side effects
Is about 26% of the shares issued by the company
Shareholder interested in
How much money
The personal make
From
The earnings of a company
And these are typically expressed in terms of earnings per share
When somebody takes the earnings after taxes
To the cheryl does the company and divide that by shares outstanding 2
Earnings per share
Fort side effects
The earnings per share of a company are .57 jen mean be
Calculated as the earnings after taxes
For shareholders
Divided by the number of shares outstanding
Although earnings after tax are running to all of them
Assets
That are on the balance sheet
In fact there is consolidation
Of
Japanese
Who is shares are not 100% owned by side effect
Beyond bricks
Example buy
Why minority shareholders
How we control the income of the minority shareholders
But that income have to be taken out
In order to get the
Earnings after tax to shareholders and
Can only that number is used in
In the calculation of the earnings per share
However only a portion of earnings are actually paid out to shareholders as cash
Does cash payments to shareholders
Are paid out as dividends
Dividends
Divided by shares outstanding
Are dividends per share sinopec paid out
About 28
Gillian jimmy b in dividends
And so the
Dividends per share
Is simply be
Total dividends
Divided by the sheraton standing once again multiplying by a million
If i stay
Dividends per share
That means that the dividend payout rate
I have to say the dividends per share divided by earnings per share what
What about 4
42% cash balances did increase from 2012 2013
Some cash was generated through increasing the negative worth
Austin capital requirement
Short-term debt and
Long-term debt in
Chris tested equity and these
Financed
The increase in fixed assets so from this introduction to the income statement
Can also remembering our discussions of
Orthopedist lectures
You can understand that they're a tremendous differences between income
Cash returns