Find jesus
Models to analyze complex
Accounting data
Are simplified input
Search for something
Of
Accounting date
It's a managerial balance sheet patrol
In the short video
That's not an example of a publicly listed company
How we choose puppy listed companies because they are
Purity regulators require that these companies publish their financial results
So if we go to toyota's website we can easily find there any report here's the annual report for
2014 all of the annual report for toyota presents
The financial
Define far more in
Nation on the actual filing with
The attic
Sophie look at the annual report and
Actually found with his dick
If we go down it
Qvc
Consolidated finance
The secret
It's actually
The same state
As
Vet advantage of the state
If you have a foot
So you can buy
Find out more information about
About each
So here is the control
Copied
From the
And report
Free coffee today
Here as an xl
File
Saudi
Numbers
Calculated
What i've done
Here and
Area is 2
For i going to die
After 6:10
The managerial balance sheet
The height of the net
Left on sergeant equal to the height of the right hand side
And i'm going to make the left hand side
What's a corporation
On the right hand side is what
Corporation owes
So the left hand side here in accounting terms
Are the outfits
On the right hand side
Are they buy bellevue
Equity
What the corporation owns is divided in the manager of balance sheet into three parts
The residual claims
Are the equity claims
These are residual claims all the assets
Are liabilities are divided into two parts
At one part is
And the other part is long term
Death
The short-term debt
The steps that occur within the space of the year
In the long-term debt
Are debts that are no
Longer than one year
Cities are
Claims
Liability holders
Yet holders
And these are claims of
Are equity holders
Can you note that all these are claims of active investors
The debt holders
What hold the death of the corporation because he loves them return the equity holders
What hold the equity of a corporation
Kevin elston and expected return
On the right hand side we're also going to divide the balance sheet
N23
Three categories
In the first category is cash
So this is really cash and short-term investments
Money market investments
Temperature in a year and addicted typically in liquid
And are not the operating invest
Edmonds theatre financial investments
Audi corporation
To the cash
Is a fine
Financial items that we have two other categories and those are the network
Working capital requirement
Andy fixed
Assets
I'll just go on a little while to talk about the network
Capital
Farming
First of all what i like to do it out a little bit of color to
Diagram and so it's not quite
In
Natural balance sheet we
We have
Just
Claims of investors on the right hand side
And on the left hand side
That we have consolidated into the working cow
Capital requirement
All of the non cash and non-cash equivalent and
Avalon short-term debt
Aspects of working capital
And then below that we have sex
Fixed assets for charts of corporation
That are of maturity longer than
What year
Getting the various items from
The assets
Attend
The liabilities and
Shareholders equity
Into the six items
I'm the manager about sheet
Is somewhat of an art
Are some items such as cash it
It's relatively easy fixed assets is largely pro
Property plant and equipment
Short-term debt
Is clearly
Short-term borrowings and
Of the long-term debt
Long-term desert little more complex clearly it includes long-term debt for the balance sheet for we've also include
Who did accrued pension and
Severance
Applications
Because these are investments
By the pictures
Holders on which toyota corporation is obliged to give a reasonable return after long-term
Penalties
How we check the
The footnotes
And in this case there's no information
Show me included those as long-term debt assuming those are from
Active investors
The treatment of deferred income taxes
One of the long-term liabilities of toyota motor corporation
If an art in this case we have taken this liability which represents
Texas that would be due if the
The accounting conventions with
With the same conventions as those used by the taxes
Dorothy's tax is the mayfield you in future years
But if these deferred income taxes are replaced as the company grows there
Did the actual amount mean never in the foreseeable future actually have to be repaid
In this case
Biddeford income taxes could
Could be treated as a part of equity recently added
Deferred income tax liability
Antiquity
You have the
Equity
From the balance sheet and we've added to that deferred inc
Income tax
Liabilities
Subtracted another number over here deferred income tax assets amounts that have been
Paid to the tax authorities but that have not yet been recognized
Through the accounting statements
Because the income was recognized my tax wanted you
What was not recognized
From
An accounting point of view
These look like prepayment of taxes and therefore
They are a deferred tax
Asset
He's actually come from other assets they're sitting here as non-current finance
Receivables
When is other category if you go to footnotes
Define that
Of that
569 billion yen
100 billion
Are actually
Deferred tax assets into
13 + 133 billion
When are deferred tax assets
Can 2004
14 what we've done with those
Is that we have subtracted them
From the fixed assets
Can subtract them
From the equity
There's a subtraction from the fixed assets
If there is
Traction
From equity
What we're in effect saving
Is that
That
Prepayment
Have taxes should not be considered as a capitalised asset
And that
Perhaps in the first
Foreseeable future that
That will never be
Claimed back by the court
Corporation add value that is already going out as an expense
So we should detect it from both equity
Can fixed assets
The final simplification and breaths the most complex simplification with
Within the manager or balance sheet
Concerns net working capital requirement
Here we add up all the components
Have a non-cash current assets
10 subtract all of the components
Oven on deck
Current liabilities
Give us a net working capital requirement
And that's how you put together a managerial balance sheet
So you see what we want to go from the somewhat
Flex
Accounting statements
Into this somewhat simplified
Six category manager or balance sheet there is summer circle t that's lost us
Nassau financial analyst have to understand that this settled he is lost
And you have to often go into the footnotes
To understand what
Which assumptions you're making an
And why you're making assumptions in order to achieve
A model
Distractible
A model that you can use it
Give the formula that we teach in the finance class
Advantage of balance sheet is a
First look
Apps
How we can use simplifications
Financial models require certifications
The endless should always understand this applications that he or she uses
In order to appreciate the output from