Today i want to talk about dcf or discounted cash flow analysis
Mini finance courses start with
Dcf
Start with a
Net present value analysis the fundamental principle and finance
Is there a business proposal will raise from value only if the
Present value of expected to
Future cash flows
Exceed initial cash outlay in a perfect market
Competitive buyers for
For business photos
Hillbilly all positive expected net
Present value
Can straps the reason why
Thomas carlyle
The great thinker of the 19th century
Dubbed economics the dismal science to perfectly competitive market positive npv projects doing
Not exist
Shake your analyst at you see a positive tv project
You've got to stop and ask yourself
What part of perfectly competitive economics is missing here that
Enable this project
Positive npv
Deposited and dvd
Evidence of an economic rent
Advent
Shows that
The returned
The productive
Resource
Wishing a good or service is greater
The cost
I love
Action
Managers
Maximize shareholder value are driven to be rent seekers
Atmosphere look up project should
2002 fire
Where the monopoly rents arise from man
Managers see value propositions they look for
Parts and services that create
Value for
4 + users the
Good or service that's created to be a must-buy
The future is going to pay a premium over the cost of production good and pv projects are now
Large
Height growth
My margin and
And more importantly
With significant barriers to entry
And they fit the resources of a company
Dallas score
Fortify
Value
An expected cash flows and discount those to present value
So here's the fundamental principle of finance the net present value of a project
Mississippi equal to
A series of cash flows
The cash flows start at time zero and recede into the
Far future
Here represented by the infinity sign
Each cash flow
Is discounted at a cost of capital
I've identified decay heroes the weighted average cost of capital which will come to an elite of actor the returned that capital
Each year's cash flow is discounted
Christian family
Find appropriate discount factor
And the question is
Is the total sum grade
Raiden zero
Note that only cash matters we bring it to present value
Silver bringing it back to x 0
These are expectations
Within the numerator
This is the expectation at x 0
Have a future cash flow for these are projections what
Once again if mpv is lesson zero value of destroyed
Imdb is greater than zero value of created
If we're dealing with a company whose shares are publicly traded
And the information becomes public on a
The given day
Did the increase in the capitalization of the shares will
Will equal net present value
Alpha project
I'm going to talk a little bit about discounting this
Discounting instantly the division buy discount factor
Can i convert future expected cash flows into their equivalent value today
Will cover the activation of the discount rate
Can the cost of capital schedule
We will cover the identifying of cash flows
In the
Capital budgeting discussion
Here we'll just look at the mechanics of discounting
The mechanics of discounting
Are the same as the mechanics of interest let's see the year one race one percent that
That means we'd be in different between having
Hundred and $1 in one year and
$100 today show
To the future value is simply the present value times 1 plus 2 inch
Interest rate
Can the interest rate is
1%
4.012
Future value in 100
Times 1.01 the present value is simply the future value
Discounted
@ 1 + 3
Rate of return for that appropriate horizon gif
Square
Expecting $101 in one year's time
Time in the in
Interest rate is 1%
And we discounted that 1.01
Can a present value of 100
If your promised $200 in one year for the price of $195 paid today the present value of the out
Uploaded $95
The present value of the inflow is simply 200 divided by 1.01
Which of the hundred $98.02
Net present value of $298.02
Midas on $95 what you have to pay out today
$3.02
The future value of the outflow is $195 times 1.010 out of $96 to the
Annette future value is
$200
Mercedes $96.95 or $3.05
You accept the deal
Note that
We could calculate that future values
Or we could calculate net present value
But we tend to
Calculate net present value in finance because
Because there is only one time
X 0 today
And yet there's an infinite number of
Future x
It's better to
Bring things to
Pet valu
Radisson
These things in a
Future value
What the principle of
Of equating
Cash flows to a
Single point in time
Is the same but
Calculations that
That i've just given
Are only for a one-year horizon interested typically quoted at a rate per annum if the rate is constant
At the one-year rate for in years we can calculate
Future value or present value
With respect to
Luann in your horizon
Can we simply can
Bring the present value
X 1 + rt india
The future value
The empire future value
Take the empire future value
The present value
He would take the future value
Can discount that buy
1 + r to the end if we had to calculate
The rate of interest
Giving a future value and present value
We just take the price relative of the future value / the present day
Value raise the power
1 overend
10 subtract 1
Ufc
5 year
Annual rate with 1% per annum the 5-year return
Would be the one year return
Race the power 501.012
The power 522
45101 that she had a promised payment in
5 years of $200
If a cost this year at $190
Anna present bow
Value
.29
-
Which is equal to
T9
Analytics
Donut dip switch
Between
Compounding
1% per year for free
Five heroes to get
5.101 percent
Is not much different from
Conciliating
1% across five years to get 5%
The reason why is
Compounding
Ford low interest rates
Does not make much difference
The compound effect
Dramatically increases
With the interest rate
Can with the years of investment
Here on the x-axis with
Show years in investment
I'm here on the y-axis
Please show the value of $1
Compounded
The years of investment
On the x-axis
At different rates in
Cell
Pet 0%
$1 compounded
10 years is
Is simply $1
And yet at 20%
$1
Compounded for 10 years
Is
Well over $6
Cash flows
In net present value analysis
Are multi period cash flows
Not just a
Single cash flow occurring app
The empire
To hear
Very useful
Youth spreadsheets
Etsy the discount rate is 10
10%
And our cash flows are $100 $200 3
$300
$400 and $500
At the end of years 1 2
The discount factor
Is simply 1 /
Oneplus are here
1 divided by 1 +10
The power t
Those translate into the
Discount factors of pi
.91
4 year one
.834 year 2.
.753 year 3
6844 n point
Your v
Multiplying a discount factor
Divided by 1 plus hearts party time
Time to cash flow
Gypsy the present value for
Each year's cash flow
And then
Adding across all years
Present value
Adr0
Here i was using an excel spreadsheet
How to do the calculations
I'm simply
Multiplying across
From the cash flow
True the discount faq
Actor
5 calculated by discount factors
As indicated
And
I calculate my present value
Simply by adding a car
Cross
I could use xl zone
Formulas
Here is the
Npv formula which is embedded in excel
Npv
Open brackets by discount rate is b1
And
I identify
Cash flows
As yours one
Nba
Before the f4
Do i get exactly the same result
Play the ride
Explicitly calculator
Why use excel formula
And if i were offered this cash flow for $1,000 today
And the michigan
Adjusted opportunity cost of capital
Were the discount rate that used to 10%
Net present value of d 1006
$5 + 20
$0.26
- $1,000
Four $65 and 20
Annuities or cash flows to pay the same amount
Every year for
For some. of time
Perpetuity
Are annuities the last forever here
Here's the formula for the present value of a perpetuity
Here's the formula
For the present value of an annuity let's look at a perpetuity paying $1
Prettier
That perpetuity would have $1 discounted
First year at 1 + r
Does $1 discount for the second year at
Cat 1 plus r squared
$1 discount this year
Pet 1 + r cubed
And so on ad infinitum
Nova take the left-hand side of this formula and multiplied by 1 divided by 1 + r
Multiplying by the discount factor
For the first year
Can we take me
Right hand side
Have the formula
And multiply it by 1/1 plus are there
Discount factor for
For the first year
Can we find the left hand
Inside out
How the formula is 1/1 + 4x present value
And the right hand side the formula his
1/1 + r
X 1
Over 1 plus
R
Which is
1/1 + r squared
Plus the second term
1 over 1 plus r squared
Times 1 over 1 plus r
Which is equal to 1/1 + r cubed
And so on for all the terms
Ad infinitum
Can we have a
Series that can be subtracted
Tv
Oneplus
Bus
Home fur
1 + r
Over 1 plus
What are
Contract here
Present value
Is simply equal to
Being that
Culver r
So the present value of a perpetuity of $1 a year
It's simply equal to 1 divided by the discount
From the formula for a perpetuity
When can derive the formula for
For an annuity
Think about a perpetuity that starts in year one
Fort collins
He won the present value
It pays $1 a year
And another purpose
Security that starts in your tea we'll call that
Youtube
Show the present value
I want to see anyone over our press
Present value of the perpetuity that starts in the year 82
Also a $1 per year perpetuity
Is 1
1 / r
However it starts in utc
So we have to bring it back to year zero present value
5 divided by 1 plus 30
The present value of the perpetuity
At your zero
Starting in your tea is 1 / r / 1 + r to the t now the present value of
Annuity starting in year 1 and going to you
Key
Is simply this
Disturbed
- this term
So it is simply
1 / r -
1 / r / 1 + rt
Value of an annuity
Senior one an indian deity
Something one -
Oneplus
What are the
The party
Call / r
I'd like to wrap up by making a distinction between
Summit confusingly similar terms when
What is effective annual rate
The second is annual percentage rate
Greater off and cool
Annual percentage rates
Vignette
These lead to
Different
Check the annual rates depending on the frequency of payment
So that's why we have
Securities
Is 10% paid semi-annually
And the other is 10% paid quarterly
These 10% pain
Semi annually and quarterly
Are annual percentage rates
Convert them into it
Effective annual rates
We have to make this
Adjustment
Looking first at the annual percentage rate
Of 10%
Payable semi-annually that
Steps equal to
5%
Actually paid
Every 6 months
The effective annual rate
Oneplus
10%
Divided by 2
To the power to my
-1
Which is equal to 10
10.25% of the earth
Effective annual rate
Is
25 basis points
Fire
Fendi
Annual percentage rate
Let's look at the second example
Defeat
Annual percentage rate
Who's the 10%
Quarterly then the effective annual rate
His equal to
Fast
0.10 2
Divided by 4
All to the power of 4
X 100
Which is equal to 10
.3
Christian
Is here you can see that
Payments on a quarterly basis
Deals
38 basis point
About the
If this was an annual purse
Percentage
Up 10%
8th annual
She want to get me
Regency theater
Your payment
Get me to a close the introduction to discounted cash-flow discounted cash-flow brings cash flow through the current
Different times to a common basis
Heat at the future or present value
By applying the time value of money
Typically bring them to present value when
When you're doing so you must be careful about the time
Remind me of cash flows
What about the discount rate
Weight you use
And of course about the definition
Outback discount rate