I want to see if you were today about forecasts
Forecasting is essential in finance because finance deals with the future
Financial statements which is a major source of information
For finance are dealing with the past
Conceal we have a small problem here
When it deals with the future because investors are basing
Their pricing of securities and
And their investment in securities
On the expected cash flows to those securities
Treasures have to protect cash flows in order to determine
Appropriate cash balances and in order to determine the
The best capital structure
Linder's used forecast to analyze credit worthiness in finance we typically use what are called pro
Proform accounting statements
Pro forma
Literally means according to the standard form its last
Accountants
Prepare performance that
Show account results as if an unusual event had not occurred to
Let's see there's a merger or a
Spinoff of a part of a company that accountants typically want to show the investors with the company would have looked like
Had that event not occurred and so the investors compare lie
Like with like if they're comparing
1 years
Earnings for the extraordinary event occurred
The previous year's earnings
It didn't occur
This is basically asking the what if question
What if
Something
Kura door didn't occur in the pro forma forecast that we make
Ashley
What if
Question
What if certain assumptions are fulfilled what does that do for the future of a company
Clearly
Forecasts are wrong but you
You can if you are good for caster specified
Confidence intervals
Around a forecast
Nearby substituting error 4
The chaos
Projected sales
Are the most important part
In
Forecasting the financial statements
Typically one uses that
The gross in sales
As the same growth number by
5 which one
Inflates
Balance sheet items
In working capital requirement
And cost balances when using the capital budget the forecast fixed assets
Edwin uses
Long-term financing of those capital assets in
In order to
Set
Long-term financing within the projections
Typically when was making for cats one wishes to have an output that
What is the short-term financing or indeed the total financing that is needed
Short-term financing or the total financing
Typically a plug
Let's go to some forecast here these are forecast for a fictitious company
Call hatcher enterprises and as you can see we've got
Numbers from the past 2012 2013 2014 for the
The income statement
Beat down cheat
Candy
Cash flow statement
The cash flow statement
Course it is
Is a statement that is derived from the income statement
And the balance sheet
So you can see i have developed
Warmest the top line
Is the revenue line
The revenue line
Is
X
The crow straight
Here i have a growth rate
10%
1 conway ave
Looking at the growth rate
Would be to say well
What is the gross
Growth rate italy
Racine
Over the last few years and human calculator
Go straight the compound growth rate
As the
2014 revenue divided for the 2012 revenue
The power
.5
Subtract 1
That gives us our historical girl
Filtrate
And then we can use that historical growth rate to generate a series of
Cost of goods sold
And other expenses assumptions
Shakira were in inflating
The cost of goods sold
And other expenses by the same number
We're also inflating
Cash capital requirements of accounts receivable inventory
And trade payables by exactly that
That seems
Figure you can see that i have input for
For the mortgage found exactly the same
Number as a previous year of the fluctuated in past years i've said what we can use exactly the same
Fixed assets that we had in previous years this
This is an assumption
That needs to be checked with the company
Handr plug
Is the
Bank line of credit
The bank line of credit simply takes two
Total assets
Extract from those total assets and liabilities that are not the bank
Bank line of credit note over here that i have interest interest is a function of the
Bank line of credit and the mortgage loan but if i calculate the interest based on the bank line of credit and then
Mortgage loan
I don't have circularity
Circularity is where the calculation
Requires the output of the calculation in order to be made
So here i get around that
Bike
Calculating interest
Based on balances
And assumed interest rates
And then i copy that number separately
5 children 2
Highlights
Chevron outputs
From our
Forecasting
Total financing
The sum of the bank line of credit and the mortgage loan
The line of credit
It seems that the mortgage loan is to
Totally available at law
Last year's level
And
The debt equity ratio
Which i took from the
Forecasted
Managerial balance sheet
I also included
A line of credit cover
This would be interesting
2/8
External supplier of
The line of credit
And
Typically
The amount of
Receivable
Candy discounted
.75
The amount of inventories and discounted by point
And compare that number
The outstanding
Collateral coverage assuming that the bank have to liquidate the collateral and ordered to repay the loan if
Default
Is 1.09
Slightly
More
Van
The total amount of
You can select various other output
From the forecasts
Occluding
Cash flow
Pro forma
Forecasts
And
Highlight forever
Part of the forecast
You think is most appropriate
Gideon now it's just you
Forecasts are
Are critically dependent on
Will used sales 2
Generator
Not only
Sales figure but the cost of goods
And the
Capital one
Ideally we would have capital budgeting
Assets envy
We also need something with his
Structure
Increased in
In order to meet fine
Airplay
Bug item as
Usually is
Forecasting
Weather
Short-term
Financing
Forecasts are
Are only as good as their son
Garbage in
Garbage out
The good forecast based on well and lysosomes
Can reduce unpleasant and
Unavoidable surprises