Finance is a part of economics
Economics is the study of the production
Distribution and consumption
Of goods and
Services
Finance
Is a small part of that
Looking at claims
Over a fence
It claims
Senior phones
Or they could be equity claims with
Schedule claims
Or they can be contingencies
Corporate finance is that part of finance that deals with clay
Claims involving corporations
Science is relatively young
Economics is been around
Ozzy
An academic discipline
Fort lee's 240 years since adam smith wrote his face
Wealth of nations
Finance as a
Pursuit in business
Has been around since corporations and business have been around
As a separate academic pursuit
It was really started in the 1950s
Corporations are
Legal persons
Legal persons are distinct
Natural person to you and i are natural persons
Legal person the corporation
Headright center
Applications that are separate from the natural person that only legal person you can have transference
Of ownership the league
Legal persons the corporations
Can survive the death of the natural persons and so problems that are in
Countered by the corporations
Can be separated from their owners
So corporations
Can contract with equity holders with debt holders
With continued claim holders within
Employees buyers and suppliers with
With the government
Corporate finance dealing with family who looks at values that are set in the marketplace corp
Corporate finance relies on accounting
The accountants catalog assassin summarize each
Each of the actions that
Take place within
In a corporation and their summaries are the raw material for the
With the analysis of financial practitioners and academics
The peanuts
That are made for financial claim
Of course simply
Exchanging bank deposits
Money in the society
Bank
Change of the bank.
Financial banking of the practice of banking is extremely important to
Corporate finance
Corporate finance relies on laws
Corporate person
Is defined in
In the laws of the country that the corporation work
Workcenter
The corporate finance itself is an interdisciplinary subject
Corporate finance is increasingly international
One of the major text
Corporate finance was written by a gentleman by the name of stephen ross
He said and many people in finance agree with them
The the
Call of managers of corporations is to maximize the
Current value per share of the existing
Maximizing shareholder wealth
This go
Who will be the default goal
Wheel considered throughout this course
Let's look at the words of jack welch
Jack welch was the chairman of ge from
1981 into
During those twin
20 years
Ge
Maximize shareholder wealth
Better than any other company
Supersize
Get jack
Dead on the face of it
Shareholder value is the dumbest idea in the world
Chevrolet value is a result
Not a strategy
Your main constituencies
She's all your employees
Your customers
And your products
Things root
Routinely ignored by academics on the grounds that
I cannot be measured that
It's a most
1 factors in all matters relating
Judgement
Ethics and morality or exactly what
What makes the difference between
Distance editions
And bad ones
Managers are the servants of
Of their employees
Their employees
Survey
Service is the key
Sustainable businesses need prom
Finance
Measures and analyzes value
This measurement and analysis of value
Is essential
To achieve the ultimate goals of this
Business
To achieving good service
Kia finance contact
If you can't measurement
It definition
The questions of the financial analyst
Should always be am i measuring the right thing and
Miami isn't the best way how closely do my assumptions and input data reflect reality
Our analysis is essential for the long-term health of the corporation
But our analysis is
Is not what we actually wish to a
Achieve which is good service
So after our financial analysis it's over
Step back for finance
Invictus
Business decisions
Finance is essential for business
The business
Is greater than finance
Good life
Mercifully
Far greater than