Today i'd like to introduce some concepts on find
Financial ratios concerning prof
Fidelity
Ratios are simply quotients where
Where we divide one number by 2nd
And the numbers come from
From the financial statements
What's a market in her
Center previous likes you to be developed many ratio as you may remember alibaba we showed a common size
Balance sheet the common size balance sheet
Simply divided each number on the balance sheet
By total assets you're able to develop race
Facials that can be compared across years and across companies to remember
Our observation that
Fb
Cash balances of alibaba had increased 73%
Of the total balance sheet
We're able to compare alibaba
With toyota motor corporation and c
How
Alibaba
Much more liquid inter
Portion of toad
Total assets
And its capitals
In terms of its short-term debt
Mountain detonate
Equity
Different from the
The capital structure
Returned to sinopec to look at the income statement
Wind-up car company with
Jillian savage md in revenue and billions arginine be in earnings after taxes
Shareholders
We've reduced those numbers simply by dividing each number on the income statement
Revenue
Reduce the income statement
2 a common size income statement
For every number was divided by revenue that
That also gave rise to a return on sales number the
Earnings after taxes shareholders
/
The revenue of a company
We linkedin
The discussion of
Income
New to the idea of
Division of
Cash to shareholders
Do the introduction
Cher
Dividends per share
Earnings are available for
4 payout
What the company made
The cash
They paid out to
Shareholders have
And the dividend payout ratio is
Listen to the dividend
Cashier / the ear inn express
That this ratio show that's not the dividend pay
Rapidly over time through
New year's 2012
2000 +
China pack
Has increase
East it's dead
Probably not
Caused by apple
Decision
Payout
So much as it is
But a decision to maintain a constant never
Apple dividends per share
Qvc that point
Two three um pressure is paid out than to
712 rising 2.2
Yeah and pressure into
That dividend was kept on
In 2004
14 from
Come 2003
However
Dividend per share
Representative for higher portion of
Earnings per share
In 2000 and
And it didn't
1000 +
13 b
The drop
Earnings after taxes
The shareholders
The dividend payout ratio
What app for
42%
2/60
Ratios are a flexible and useful family of tools at the analyst looks at ratios over time
Time
And between companies any books that the
Differences or consistency of the ratios
I as long as we have a good analytical reason for calculating a set of ratios and as long as the animals control
A compelling story
About the ratios
10 ratio analysis that is performed is used for
The question is can the analyst tell a good story
What is happening in the company
Why is it happening
Now let's look at a set of ratio is an
Andis concerned
Composition of
Return on equity
Return on equity or roa
Is the most broad measure of perform
Available from ratios that are calculated from annual accounting statements of
Alpha company
Far away is simply the earnings after tax that
That are attributable to shareholders
Divided by shareholders equity
I just like to go into the definition
Ave
Equity forum
From the point of view of the roex
Depression
First note that
Earnings
Reported on the income statement
Are earnings over a. of time typically a year
I hear of showing earnings from. 02
. 1
Equity
Is a stock at a given point in time
Typically the financial statements for show earnings for a year
And the ending equity for the year
So we have a time inconsistency here
We could calculate
Re
Simply as
The earnings over the period
/ and equity
This is the simplest way because
Guys were typically given the balance sheet of fp
Period end
Amber given the earnings
For the period
But you can see it somewhat inconsistent
Because you're saying that there's a return to equity
Where the equity is
Is the final equity
Another possibility that we could use
His weed use the
Earnings
For the period
Divided by the equity at the beginning of the period
This is a certain logic
Investors are always looking at one year
Time horizons
Method that we use in this course
Looks at
Roa
As the earnings
/ the average equity over the period
I answer the question which is the appropriate method
By endorsing the third method
But no this is not an absolute right or wrong
How do you frequently see the other two methods when
When you look at the ratio analysis of roi for other analysts
We returned it
To the state
Statements of toyota motor corporation in order to calculate return on equity
And as you can see we are
You're using
The income attributable to shareholders from
For the income statement
Amber dividing it by an average of
Two numbers from the balance sheet
Going to the balance sheet
You can see the word f***
Focusing on
The
Equity as defined by the managerial balance sheet
Who are equity here
Is the
Top book equity and we have an average of the beginning and ending year
Equity
From the balance sheet
The return on equity
Shareholders of toyota motor corporation
Girls from chess
3.11 percent in 2012
Wells
Up to 12.77%
In 2014
We're also going to look at
Ii
Company
When looking at return on equity and this company is the
The rose group
4 hoffman laroche
Hoffman laroche is the third largest
Firm
Informa farm
Pharmaceuticals in the world after all
Johnson & johnson and pfizer
Rush is based in switzerland
Shouldn't that shares are listed
On the fix swiss exchange
Irish is famous
Valium and i
Hyatt highly successful antiretroviral therapy drugs it's also famous for tammy
Flu
And it owns the u.s. corporation
Genetech
Here we show the calculation of
Roaches
Return on equity
In the same way that we calculated
Toyota's return on equity
Note however that the years are reversed
We're showing both
Roshe
And toyotas years in the order that they're showing on their financial statements
In 2012 roche had a return on equity of 75%
Where is toyota head
How to return on equity
811 %
Roaches are
He was dick
Climbing whereas toy
Toyota's roa
Was in
Creasing
One can analyze the return on equity
By its component part
Christoval
One can break return on equity which is simply earnings after tax / equity
Into two parts by multiplying bernie
Earnings after taxes
/ equity x 1 or assets / assets
And shifting the
Terms
Define that
Return on equity
Simply return on assets
X
Leverage
We can further decompose return on equity by
Decomposing return on assets
Return on assets
Can be decomposed into return on sales
Data stay running after tax divided by sales
X asset turnover
Sales divided by assets
Set this construct
Ai dupont
Identity
Named after the american
Chemical giant
Tupac
Roa
Can be broken into roa x leverage
Can be broken into ros
X
Sales
Over assets
Going back to whole foods
Rather high but
Dropping roa one
One can see that
Operating efficiency that it's a earnings after taxes
Over sales which is the return on sales
Having roughly constant
The same is also true with acid deficiency this is the asset turnover
Asset turnover is roughly constant
What has changed
Yes
Leverage has dropped
From
3.48 times 2
2.58 times
Drop of leverage
Has reduced
The roa
For toyota the increase in
Return on equity is
It's largely driven
By the operating efficiency
I have to say the return on sales
Running after taxes
Divided by sales
Has gone from about 2%
How about san fran
There's also been an increase in
Acid deficiency or in sales turnover that's gone up slightly but net
Leverage
Actually
Decreased slightly
So these two factors primarily the
The sales margin return on sales
Accounts for the
Rapid increase
Frweed
At the end of the day however
The roa of hoffman the rose is still
Much larger than the roa
Ave
Toyota would anybody wish to buy toyota shares
Given the army is so much higher for
4 hoffman laroche
Vin for toyota
The answer of course is yes
The answer comes
From the difference between the
Market price
At which the shares of hoffman-laroche can be bought
Relative to their book price
And the market price at which toyota shares can be
Peapod
Relative to their book price
The book value per share
Of hot
Hoffman larosa's
Is
Swiss francs
The market
Cher
Best pranks
To the market to book ratio of hoffman the roshes
Is 7.663
Book value per share of toyota corporation is 4
4196 year the end-of-year share price
558 yen
Show the market people
Book ratio
For toyota it
Is 1.8
Is a much higher market price
My stuff be paid
By shareholders
Hoffman the row
Roshe
Denver
5 shareholders of
Half toyota we can express that in
In terms of the price earnings ratio
Hoffman laroche
The price-earnings ratio
Is simply be
Price per share
Divided by the earnings
Available to shareholders
Show the price of earnings ratio
Hoffman roshes 20
4x
Versus the price earnings ratio
After
Toyota
Of 13x
The inverse of
Price-earnings ratio is
Is the earnings yield
The earnings yield is an analog
Ave
The return on equity
But in the earnings yield
We the colonel's after taxes
There are available to shareholders to
Divided by the stock price
Shareholders have to pay in order to get that yield
The earnings yield of course is more volatile
Then return on equity using the
Book value of the company
But the earnings yield is forward-looking for both book returns
And market returns
Have their advantages
In conclusion financial ratio express
Flexible approach
Understanding