I'd like to spend a little time to talk
Talk about growth
In the last few
Electric repair looking at various ratio was
Pengrowth actually could be
Be considered a ratio
We see the destructive effect
Of unrestrained growth
At same time as we see the benefits we're escaping from
Property for everyone
How can our grasp
Previous lecturer i mentioned that the default go
Finances
Maximizing shareholder wealth
Deco pushes managers
To pursue profitable growth
If we as a society believe
Pet unrestrained growth
Is destructive
The only way to incentivize managers approach
Hope it leads to death
Sign policies
Lipstick
Social cost
Are put in the
Structures of firms
Responsible managers will respond appropriately
Growth will
Tempered that means that responsible managers
Should be in the forefront of
Vision
The social costs
Of their actions
And so they can help craft policies that allowed this internalization
Five economic externalities
David recent article
Kinsey published by three of its researchers
That have the title
Grow fast or die slow
Article was written about the software industry
Treat and the researchers came to the conclusion
That in the software industry
Over the last 30 years companies did not grow fast
Then basically
They were highly addressed
And likely to die
Guy
The reasons for this in software is it is very low barriers to entry patents and software
Fort worth
Very much because they can be easily
Circumnavigated
The math of economies of scale and there is abstention brand recognition
Noah from me to grow quickly
To achieve that recognition and their economies of scale
Near me not be true and other industries and an analyst has
After analyzed
The effects of growth and
And the industry structure
Sherman what the
Appropriate growth rate for a firm its
I've been talking about growth rates
So let's put it in numerical terms the appropriate row 3 to use in the car
Compound annual growth rate
Cagr
Multi-year
Into a standard annual compound growth
Penguin calculate that something by taking a price
Price relative
Ken. value
/ the zero. value and
Raising up the power
Power 104 in
Where in is the number of year periods are there
Subtract 1 from now
Obviously if x 0 is reduced to
Near zero
Then the compound annual growth rate explodes
A second related problem is
The
Variables
Go through 0 during the period self
Love me
Positive or negative value
What's the negative to a positive value
That means that the growth rate of someone time
Calgon twins
And finally
Values are small relative the other accounts on
An income statement
Bounce sheet
Then even if a compound annual growth rate is high
Hi
Then it might not be
Be very
Time calculator
Three-year compound annual growth
Retreat energy can see what we do it 72
Take me last year 2014 / the first year
The power point
.5 + 2
1 given
Getting a very low growth rate
.7%
Annual come
Compound growth rate
Lovin you
Bring it together with an n
Increase of 13
1%
Appreciation and amortization and depletion
Then that translates in
Earnings
Going to the balance sheet
One can see that total assets are
Are growing at a
The compound annual growth rate
Curious into a positive
40% per year over the
2 years
But since both of these are negative numbers
What were seen is an increase in the negative amount of the working capital requirement
Financing
March of the
Fixed assets
About roach weed
We have one two three
4 years of data
And that means that
What are our compound annual growth rate
Is calculated by raising
Price relative
Koozies
You can see that for
Roshe
Sales are growing only a test
Note 3.7
Percent per annum
All the royalties are going at 5
At these represent
Only about 5% of
The fastest growing item on roosevelt
Intangible assets
Going at
An average 36%
Branham
Not only is growing rapidly but
What number is larger
Relative to
Do other non-current assets
Being exceeded only by property plant and equipment
What are these intangible assets
Visa purchases by rush
Of patents
And the development in
Internally through research of patents
Unlike the software industry
Patent protection in pharmaceuticals
He's actually very strong these
Keystone key barriers to entry for roche
In allowing it
To enjoy profitability i want to do a new concept the
Self sustainable growth rate
Self-esteem
Grow
New equity comes available only from retained earnings
The firm does not have any equity
Fern grows 2
To the retention of
Connected abs short-term and long-term debt
Proportion
As the new equity from the returned on
I answered it goes
Game rated x
We have the
Company with ak
Capital structure
And if a company grows by 10% that
That 10% growth
Will have to be supported by a growth in a set
So that she needs a proportionate girl
Girls in athens
Portal
So cash working capital requirement in fixed assets all girl by
X 10%
And then i have to be financed
If the capital structure is to remain the same short-term debt and
Long-term debt also have to be increased by 10%
Anti
Equity
All you have to go up
By 10% at 10%
Equity increase
Fast come from
Mary free is 10% growth is sustainable without dividends
If are we is 20%
What is sustainable
With 10%
Healthy returns on equity being paid out and 10% being retained
If the payout rate is 50%
That's the idea of the self sustainable growth rate
In general
Sales meet assets to generate the growth
The couch cushion for liquidity the working capital requirement
And fixed assets
Property including intellectual property plant and equipment
A default assumption that
That is to say a good starting point assumption
Is the growth in
Sales requires a proportionate grow in assets
Of course if the company has massive economies of scale as to some song
Software network base forms this assumption may be wrong
Let's keep it for the moment let's also assume that tapping equity markets is difficult
The firm wishes to keep its current capital structure in this case this
Self sustainable growth rate
Can be calculated as
The retention rate
X 3 turn on equity
Retention rate is simply the
The earnings per share minus the dividend per share divided by the earnings per share times the return on investment
Let's look
Look at josh's cell
Stainable growth rate
The retention rate
Is a
About 28%
In
Having dropped from 40%
In 2013
Is low retention rates they are x
5 very high returns on equity
The shelf sustainable growth rate
Rangers in the three years that we have data for
From 14% to
- 28%
And this self sustainable growth rate
Is my
Much higher
In the compound annual growth rate
In sales
For the compound annual growth rate
That we see on the balance sheet
Giving plenty of room
Hoffman laroche to deliver
Orchard expand if wish to do so
Text to sign up
It had retention rates of the
57% witch
Dropped
- 39% its return on equity was relatively low
So when you multiply through the
Retention rate times the return on equity
We find a self sustainable growth rate
Ranging from 3 to
About 7%
Now that's sustainable growth rate
Actually
Exceeds the growth rate in revenues
But if you look at the
Crossfit in assets on the balance sheet
You can see the growth and axis exceeding the self sustainable growth rate
Which leads one to believe that
Side effects
After either increases leverage that have to say it's debt equity ratio
Ford sync external financing
Orange future
Reduce its growth rate
Bring to a conclusion the
.7 ways to make about growth
Obviously growth can be
Be critical to the
The firm analyzing the financial statements
Using compound annual growth rates is
Is there a easy and i can help
Help the allies gain insight into the
The firm sustainability of growth should be analyzed
Growth needs
Financing
And financing is expensive
So calculating that are self sustainable growth rate is useful and within public policy growth
Has it
Applications for
For sustainability
Event
Autonomy
End of the
Environment managers of the firm even though they're constrained
Maximize the wealth of shareholders have a duty to help them
Attraction of public policy to enable sustainability at the macro-level