Hello today i want to talk about jobs in v
Finance
Most people that are taking this course
Candice program are looking for a job at the end of the university
We're and so it just messing with them to know what jobs
Baby available at
If i go into finance
Fat in financial institutions run 2
Confined
Jobs in server
Servicing the
The financial needs of non-financial it's too
And it's also financial work in non financial institute
Financial work involves claims as i mentioned before i leave her claims
Car debt claims
Equity claims are
Mutual claims
Andrew
Derivatives are contingent claims
Fun apps working financially
Stations
Involves creating or destroying claims
Buying or selling claims
Fat analyzer for providing information about the claims
Super example if a bank teller i take
A deposit from a customer that creates a financial claim it creates a death claim that
Septa customer has over
Citibank
App for example if i am a
Officer of a bank and i have to do the credit analysis
For the
Credit worthiness of a potential bar work then i analyze the
The ability of the borrower to make repayments on his
His or her leg
Investment bank
Manicure at
As part of the process of helping a company to issue equity
How to write a prospectus
Net prospectus disc
Closes in a full and clear wave
All of the information
What is material to
New investors
Valuing bad company
Private equity professional on
On the southside
Be encouraged insurance company or pension fund
To invest in a new private equity fund
Founded by side
A private equity
Fat officer
May
Sift through the company models
50 different companies
Determining which ones are appropriate
Become investees of the private equity fund
There are many jobs in financial institute
Cushions
That have to do with compliance
Compliance is
The issues of
Evolving laws and regulations
How to kevin
If i activities
Making sure that financial institutions comply with them
That when they don't
Comply with the regulations
The day
Understanding mistakes and correct them steaks quickly
Other careers in finance
I involve
Working in financial functions in one financial institute
Alice temperley under the chief executive officer of a corporation and hit
It involves two
Two streams the
The treasury
Can control
Treasury concerns cash
Show all flows out
Of cash within and without the corporation that have to do with corporation
Are the job of the treasurer
He or she manages petty cash bank accounts and investments
And
Are the treasurer also raises debt and equity
Amex payments of interest on the debt and the
Dividends on the equity
The other function under the chief financial officer is control
Controller keeps track of the financial flows and stocks of the corporation and is responsible for producing
Sing at the accounting and financial statements
Av controller calculator
And optimizes and pays taxes and the controller is also responsible for
Corporate secretary activity
Company secretary is not that personal assistant the ball
Boss that serves as a receptionist
Keeps track of his
Calendar and it takes telephone calls
Company secretary to something much more important
Especially for a listed company
Have a company secretary
Make sure that the
Servants of the shareholders
The board of directors
People actually control
Call the company
Their obligations their legal obligations
That company
The career path
Youtube
Financial
Non-financial corporations
Awesome ghosts
True financial corp
Operations
For example
They're going to work
Treasury
Of a company
First work at a bank
People that are working
If we first work
Weather
Cool
4 4
A treasury
A background in law
What is very useful
So
A typical path to the cfo of a company
Is to join treasury or control and then work yourself up to
In any job
What you should do is
Understand how you provide value to the
Corporation
How you can increase the value to that cat
Only then can you assess your
Your own worth
2 year old corporation
And how you're creating value for